Finding aid to the Julia Harwood Caverno Papers CA.MS.00043
Smith College Archives
Julia Harwood Caverno Papers
1885-1949
Smith College Archives
Caverno, Julia Harwood.
CA.MS.00043
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
The collection documents the life and career of Julia Harwood Caverno, as a member of the Greek Department.
Biographical / Historical
Julia Harwood Caverno was born to Rev. Charles and Anna Watson Caverno on December 19, 1862 in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. She received both her B.A. and M.A. degrees from Smith College in 1887 and 1890 respectively. While she was working on her M.A., Caverno taught Greek and Latin at the Grant Collegiate Institute in Chicago (1887-1893).
In 1893 Caverno came to Smith College as an instructor in Greek. She was soon promoted to a full professor. Between 1912 and her retirement in 1931, she served as the head of the department. Upon her retirement, Caverno's past students showed their respect for her by establishing the Julia Harwood Caverno Prize, which is awarded annually to a student for excellence in Greek. Julia Harwood Caverno died on February 2, 1949.
The Caverno Room in Smith College's Neilson Library is named in her honor.
Scope and Contents
The Julia Harwood Caverno Papers contain biographical materials, correspondence, photographs, publications, speeches, lecture notes, student recommendations, part of her work for her Master's thesis and her scrapbook.
Related Material
Class of 1887 Records
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Caverno, Julia Harwood.; Caverno, Julia Harwood.
- Biographical Materials, 1887-1949; undated (Box 696, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1893-1943; undated (Box 696, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Grierson, 1901-41 (Box 696, Folder 3)
- Photographs, 1887; n. d. (Box 696, Folder 4)
- Publication: The Figures of Homer, 1892 (Box 696, Folder 5)
- Publication: "The Messenger in Greek Tragedy", 1917 (Box 696, Folder 6)
- Publication: "So Big", undated (Box 696, Folder 7)
- Publication: "How Can the Colleges and High Schools cooperate to stimulate an interest in the study of Greek?", 1908 (Box 696, Folder 8)
- Lecture Notes, undated (Box 696, Folder 9)
- Speeches, 1915-39 (Box 696, Folder 10)
- Student Recommendations, 1904-21 (Box 696, Folder 11)
- Master's Thesis, 1889-90 (Box 696, Folder 12)
- Retirement, 1931 (Box 696, Folder 13)
- Scrapbook, 1885-1943 (Box 696, Folder 14)